#Encodergasm Presents
～
あん？
Such pretty eyes.
（フェイ）眉目秀麗
明眸皓歯(めいぼうこうし)
You've pretty eyes and a smile to match.
Lookin' to score riches?
一獲千金
I welcome all.
先客万来
"Herbal Medicine Shop"
Ya know the first rule in combat?
（フェイ）戦いの基本を知ってる？
...to get the first attack.
先制攻撃よ
What an extended greeting this is.
丁重なお迎えだこと
I didn't know that the sure-shot and master of poker...
（ゴードン）
早撃ちとポーカーの名手
...the legendary female gambler Poker Alice was still alive.
伝説の女ギャンブラー
ポーカーアリスか
生きていたとは知らなかったな
ふん 彼女が生きてれば219歳よ
If she was still alive, she'd be 219 years old now.
Of course.  You sure don't look over 200.
（ゴードン）確かに君は
200歳を超えているとは思えないな
（フェイ）うっ ううーん
Besides, Alice never lost during her lifetime.
（ゴードン）それに
アリスは生涯 負けたことがない
She kept winning, without cheating.
イカサマもせず もうけ続けた
You have a way to prove that?
証拠があって言ってんのかしら？
I hear you are carrying a large debt.
（ゴードン）
君には莫大(ばくだい)な借金があるそうだな
Which do you prefer... the police, or my establishment?
警察と私の店と
どちらがお好みかな？
A prophecy?
（スパイク）お告げねぇ
Charlie said, "Only hands can wash hands."
（ジェット）チャーリーは言った
“手は手でなければ洗えない”
"If you want to receive, you must first give."
“得ようと思ったら
まず与えよ”ってな
Hey, doesn't that mean that Charlie is telling us to just do it?
てことは どういうことだ？
チャーリーは
やれって言ってるんじゃねえのか？
へへっ そうだろ？
Right?
チャーリー･パーカーが
ゲーテの格言 吐くかね？
Do you think Charlie Parker would quote Goethe?
Oh come on, it's all part of the dream I had.
いいだろ 夢の話なんだから
The way things go, I say that even the hard-earned...
虎の子の5000ウーロンも
夢と消えるのが落ちだな
...5000 woolongs will disappear with your dream.
Let me tell you something, Spike...
言っとくがな スパイク
This is a no smoking area.
ここは禁煙だ
You shouldn't play.  Your eyes are too good for this.
（ジェット）お前は やるなよ
目が良すぎるんだからな
They'll kick us out if you win too much.
下手に稼ぐと つまみ出される
Then don't bring me here.
じゃあ 連れてくんなよ
Pray, man.
（スパイク）祈りな
（アントニオ）やったあ
（スパイク）もらってくぜ
I'll take one.
ウーフー フフッ
Small jack.
（フェイ）スモールジャックです
（客たち）おーっ
I'll play a few.
遊ばせてもらうぜ
Must be him.
（フェイ）こいつか
ナイスジャッキー
Nice, Jackie.
The target will sit at a blackjack table, and lose at a certain point.
（ゴードン）
相手はブラックジャック台に来て
適当なところで負ける
Of course, you will help him with that.
もちろん君も それに協力する
And, he will hand you the last chip he has as a dealer's chip.
そして最後に残した１枚のチップを
ディーラーチップとして君に渡す
And what about it?
それが何なのよ
It's something that'll make your debt...
君の借金など
宇宙の中の１秒に等しくなるものだ
...as small as one tiny second in this universe.
Last game.
ラストです
I'm not lucky, nor am I nimble.
俺は運がいいわけでも
腕がいいわけでもないんだ
Then what are you?
じゃ 何が？
Generous.
きっぷがいいのさ
Blackjack.
ブラックジャックです
You got me.  I give up.
やられたな　まいった まいった
I'll take this as a memento.
記念にもらっとくぜ
Huh?
えっ？ ちょっと待ってよ
Wait a minute!
Hold up!
待ちなさいよ！
あん？
Hey, you!
ちょっと あんた
どこが きっぷがいいのよ
話が違うじゃない
What part of you is generous?
This wasn't the plan I heard!
I thought you were supposed to give me the last chip!
最後の１枚は
こっちに よこすはずでしょ
Why should I?
なんでだよ　イカサマ勝負に
付き合ってやったんだぜ
I played along with you and your cheats!
Did you hear that?
（男性客１）おい 聞いたか？
イカサマだってよ
Cheating!
That for real?
（男性客２）本当かよ
The dealer has been cheating!
（女性客１）ディーラーが
イカサマやってんだって
（フェイ）なっ！
Can you come with me to the office?
ちょっと事務所に
来ていただけませんか
Why?
なんで？
What do you want?
何だよ
You piece of!
野郎！
ええい
Come on...
おいおい ここのカジノは
フィットネスまでやってるのかい？
Does this casino also run a fitness club?
It's showtime!
ショータイムよ
Heh heh.  Pardon me here.
へへえ ちょっとごめんよ　うん？
Spike...
スパイク
よし
All right.
Jet.
（スパイク）ジェット
That's why I told you not to...
だから やるなと言っただろが
That's not it!  But we gotta split!
（スパイク）そうじゃねえよ
とにかく逃げるぜ
I haven't cashed these in yet!
まだ金に換えてねんだぞ　おーい
HEY!!
（フェイの悲鳴）
He doesn't have it.  The chip is a fake.
（男１）やはり持っていません
チップは偽物です
Neither you nor your boss realize why we cooked up this whole thing...
（ゴードン）何のために
この茶番を仕組んだか―
お前もお前たちのボスも
分かってないようだな
あのチップが警察の手に渡ったら
全ては終わりだ
If that chip falls into police hands...
It's all over!
（男２）ボス あの女
まだ見つかりませんぜ
Boss, we still can't find that broad.
Find her!
捜せ！ 賞金を懸けてもいい
Put a reward on her if you have to!
（フェイ）ちょっと
Wait a sec!
Why is my reward for bringing ya back...
ここまで運んでやったお礼が
どうしてこうなんのよ
...being trapped in here?!
I see.  She smells like money to you too, huh?
そうか やっぱり この姉ちゃんは
金のにおいがするか
You have GOT to be kidding!
ばか言わないで
Jet, how much did you have?
ジェット いくらもうけてた？
Oh, 200K.  Easy.
軽く20万は いってたな
誰がパーにした？
And who put it all to naught?
何よ 20万ぽっち
私の借金に比べたら…
What, only 200K?
That's nothing compared to my debt...
大体ね 言いがかりにも
ほどがあるんじゃない？
Besides, don't you think this is a bit much for a false accusation?
まっ あのモノ･キャリアなら
40万で売れるな
Well, that mono-carrier should sell for about 400K.
If you had just given me that chip, we wouldn't have had a problem.
（フェイ）
あんたがチップを素直に渡せば
何も問題はなかったのよ
Chip?
（ジェット）チップが？
Yeah!
（フェイ）そうよ
がー ぐあー ぺっ
（ジェット）
いえーっ きったねえな
Disgusting.
それをちゃんとゴードンに渡せば
いくらだってくれるわ
If you give that to Gordon, he'll give you as much as you want.
そうよ そうしましょ
Yeah, let's do that!
I don't know any guy named Gordon...
（スパイク）
俺はゴードンなんてやつは
知らねえし―
...nor do I want to believe your stories.
お前の話を信用する気もないね
Wait a minute!
ちょっと
Let's go, Ein.
行くぜ アイン
Are you listening to me?  Come on!
It's a chip.
チップだ
Of course it's a chip.
（スパイク）そりゃ チップだろ
I don't mean that kind of chip.  There's a microchip in this thing.
そうじゃねえ　この中に
マイクロチップが仕込まれてるんだ
ふーん
（パンチ）アミーゴ！
賞金首のことならお任せ
AMIGO!  Leave it to us for bounty information!
Thanks for waiting!  It's time for BIG SHOT!
（ジュディ）お待ちかね
ビッグショットの時間よ
（ジェット）こりゃあ…
（ジュディ）さーて
This is...
So, first up this week is?
（ジュディ）
今週のトップバッターは？
（パンチ）
警察に渡すには もったいない彼女
見かけによらず常習犯
It's a shame we have to hand her to the police.  She doesn't look it, but...
Hey, Spike!
...she's a real mean one.  Faye Valentine.
（パンチ）
警察に渡すには もったいない彼女
見かけによらず常習犯
おい スパイク！
フェイ･ヴァレンタインだ
The bounty is a whopping 6 million!  A real deal!
（ジュディ）うーん
賞金はなんと600万　お買い得よ
First come, first served.
Hey, Jet!
（スパイク）おい ジェット
（パンチ）さあ 早い者勝ちだ
頑張ってね カウボーイズ
Good luck, cowboys!
I've been waiting for you.
会いたかったよ
（フェイ）言っとくけど
逃げるつもりじゃなかったのよ
First off, let me tell you that I didn't intend to run.
（ゴードン）
信じてたさ　今どこだ？
I trust you.  Where are you?
An old fishing ship near the gate.
ゲートにある 古臭い漁船
チップも彼らが持っているわ
だから早く
They have the chip.
So hurry up and...
何よ
What?
いやあ 俺たちも
大人げなかったなと思ってな
Well, we thought we were being immature.
若い身空の女を
こんな所に放っちまってさ
To leave a young woman in a place like this.
変なこと考えてんじゃ
ないでしょうね
You aren't thinking weird thoughts, are you?
No, we thought we'd escort you to a place more considerate of your situation.
（ジェット）
なあに もっと気の利いた所に
ご案内するだけさ
Oh, and where would that be?
あーら どこかしら
The police.
（ジェット･スパイク）警察
（ジェット）
20万なんて せこいこと言って
本当 悪かったよ
We're sorry that we were so cheap earlier with the 200K bit...
...Faye Valentine.
フェイ･ヴァレンタイン
私 賞金でも懸かってるわけ？
What, there's a bounty on me?
A whopping 6 million.
（スパイク）なんと600万もね
なーんだ 600万ぽっちか
What... only 6 million?
お前 いくら借金してんだ？
How much ARE you in debt?
Come on, please!  Anywhere but the police!
ねえ お願い
警察だけは行きたくないの
（ジェット）
警察じゃなきゃ 金はもらえん
Only the police would give us money.
私は ひとところに とどまること
しちゃいけないのよ
My mother's last will was for me to not be in any place for too long!
母の遺言なの
ああ はいはい
Yeah, yeah...
My family have always been "Romanies," wandering about in search of love.
私たちの一族は
愛を求めて放浪するロマニーなの
You don't know anything, do you?  That's another term for Gypsies!
（フェイ）学のない男ね
ジプシーのことよ
Everyone else, like you guys, with no pride in their lives are called "Gorgio."
それ以外の誇りを持たない
あんたたちみたいな人間を―
ゴールジュって呼ぶのよ
I'm fine with being a "Gorgio."
（ジェット）ゴールジュ 結構
ああー 呼んでるわ
自然が私を呼んでるの
It's calling me...  The great outdoors is calling out to me...
You can do all of this with the cops.
（ジェット）警察でしろ
出航だ ジェット
Let's go, Jet.
（フェイ）ううん 分かったわよ
逃げないから片手ぐらい外してよ
Oh, fine.  I won't run.  At least untie one hand!
これじゃトイレもできないでしょ
I can't even go to the bathroom like this!
Man, we got one yappy woman here...
たく うるせえ女だぜ
（ジェット）
ぬれ手に あわとでも言うのかね
Like taking candy from a baby.
損して得取れってやつさ
More like a small sacrifice for a large reward.
チャーリーは言ってたもんな
“得ようと思ったら まず与えよ”
As Charlie said, "If you want to receive, you must first give."
夢のお告げも
まんざら捨てたもんじゃねえ
I guess what I see in dreams is worth something once in a while...
Ow...
てえーっ
何しやがる
What do you think you're doing?
君たちが何者か知らないが
チップを返してもらおうか
I don't know who you are...
...but I would like the chip back.
（ジェット）
あんたが何者か知らねえが
お断りだね
...but I refuse.
It's just a chip that means nothing to you.
（ゴードン）君たちには
無意味な ただのチップだろ
Although we can sell what's IN the chip for a pretty penny.
（ジェット）
その中のもんは高く売れそうだぜ
There was a decryption program called Crypt-Breaker...
確か３年ほど前にＳＩＴで
開発された暗号解読プログラム―
...that was developed by SIT three years ago.
クリプトブレイカーってのがある
Rumors say that right after its completion, the programmer was killed,
完成直後に
プログラマーが殺されて―
and the program went into the black market.
闇ルートに流れたって
うわさのなあ
It's a "magic key" that can decode and unlock almost every protection code.
何しろ ほとんどの暗号を解読して
プロテクトを外せる
言ってみりゃ
魔法の鍵ってわけだな
But that program itself was encoded.
ところがそのプログラム自体が
暗号化されちまってた
So, there was a need to find the key to open the program.
それ自体を開ける鍵が
必要だってわけだ
警察とＩ.Ｓ.Ｓ.Ｐが
血眼になって―
I heard rumors that both the cops and the ISSP were parting hairs to find the key...
そいつを捜してたって
うわさだが―
へへっ まさか こんな所で
お目にかかれるとはな
I never thought I would see it in a place like this.
なかなか やり手のようだ
You're pretty good.
昔 Ｉ.Ｓ.Ｓ.Ｐって
ヤクザな商売してたもんでね
I used to work in a shady place called the ISSP.
I'm sure the casino was to take attention away from...
カジノなら
大金を扱っても目立たんし―
警察の目も
欺けるって寸法だろうが―
...the large sum of money and to fool the cops...
You just chose the wrong day.
日が悪かったな
Of course, this thing is useless for us as well.
もちろん俺たちが持ってても
役に立たん代物だ
It would only be proper to give it to the cops.
警察に渡すのが筋だろう
I'll pay.
（ゴードン）金を払おう
300 million...  Nah, too much.  How about 30 million?
（ジェット）３億とは言わん
3000万でどうだ？
Not bad for the price of a magic key, eh?
魔法の鍵の値段としちゃあ
安いもんだろ
All right...
よかろう
Okay, 6 million turns into 30 million.
（ジェット）
ＯＫ　600万が3000万だ
The money just keeps growing...
（スパイク）わらしべ長者かよ
Don't get caught off-guard.
（ジェット）ぬかるなよ
Okey dokey.
（スパイク）オーキードーキ！
今どき現金指定とはな
Someone who specifies cash up front is rare nowadays.
古いタイプの男なんでね
I'm an old-fashioned guy.
All right.
（ゴードン）いいかね
お互い三つ数える
We'll both count to three.
そこでこちらは
トランクのマグネットを切り―
At which point, we will release the magnetic field of the suitcase...
そちらに飛ばす
...and send it that way.
そちらはチップをこちらへ飛ばす
You toss the chip our way.
Okay.
（スパイク）ＯＫだ
I'm trusting you...
頼んだぜ
When you confirm that we got the chip, sink that ship.
チップを確認したら 船ごと落とせ
Roger.
Let's go!
行くぜ
One.
（スパイク）１
Two.
Three.
何っ？
シャッターは開けるもんだ
Shutters are meant to be OPENED!
What!?
何っ？
はーい ゴールジュ
Hi, "Gorgio."
よお ロマニー
Hey, "Romani."
バーイ
Bye!
Don't let her get away!  Fire!!
逃がすな！ 撃てえ！
くそっ
Shit!
Jet, let's get outta here!
（スパイク）
ジェット ずらかるぜ！
（ジェット）オーライ！
All right!
Get them!  Get them!  What the hell are you doing!?
落とせ 落とせ！ 何をしている
She dropped chaff!
（男１）チャフを まきやがった
（男２）何？
What?
（男１）ミサイル接近！
Missiles are approaching!
That wench...
あの女
It's only proper to use it.
使っちまうのが正解だ
わらしべ長者のやり直しか
Guess we have to build up again from square one.
That's cheating!
（客）イカサマだ！
Too much time has passed by...
Aishiteta to nageku niwa
...to lament that we were deeply in love.
Amarinimo toki wa sugite shimatta
The wind keeps blowing, while my heart...
Mada kokoro no hokorobi wo
...cannot heal all the tears in it.
lyasenu mama kaze ga fuiteru
Someone, cry for me with parched eyes.
Kawaita hitomi de dareka naite kure
The real folk blues.
The real folk blues
I only want to know what true sadness is.
Honto no kanashimi ga shiritai dake
Sitting in muddy water...
Doro no kawa ni tsukatta
...isn't such a bad life...
Jinsei mo waruku wa nai
...if it ends after the first time...
Ichido kiri de owaru nara
～
It sucks... this world is such an unruly place.
（ジェット）
嫌だねえ　物騒な世の中だ
不況不況で子供はキレるか
Economic recession everywhere, making kids lose their minds...
（スパイク）
おい 新聞 見てる場合かよ
Come on, this isn't the time to be reading the paper!
Things aboard the Bebop are becoming even more unruly!
ビバップの中のほうが
よっぽど物騒なことになってんぞ
（ジェット）かわいいもんだろうが
これ 見てみろ
Bah, this is nothing!
Look at this... terrorists!
テロだとよ
ガニメデをぶっ飛ばすつもりらしい
Apparently they want to blow Ganymede up.
（スパイク）
ああ？ 自然保護団体か
Oh?  Environmental Protection Society?
Perfect!  We can have them take care of this fleabag.
ちょうどいい　そいつらに
この けだもの引き取ってもらえ
Next episode: Gateway Shuffle.
（ジェット）
次回「ゲイトウェイ･シャッフル」
Man, I'M about to lose it.
（スパイク）こっちがキレそうだ